Gerald Smith

43 Sydney Street, Salt Lake City, Utah, 84103 garald.smith@youremail.com (123) 456-7890

A detail-focused and dedicated makeup artist with 14 years of experience, including working for TV networks, fashion designers, magazines, and well-known photographers. Achieved an associate degree in cosmetology from Santa Monica College. Proven ability to multitask in fast-paced and high-pressure environments to meet tight deadlines and achieve complex Looks. Impressive communication and customer service skills, which assist in encouraging returning customers and client loyalty.

Education

Associate in Science in Cosmetology Santa Monica College, Santa Monica, CA September 2005 - June 2007

Key Skills

- Film, print, bridal, and fashion makeup
- Hairstyling
- Airbrushing and body makeup application
- Proficient multitasker
- Energetic working attitude
- Understanding of how lighting and angles affect makeup

Professional Experience

Makeup Artist

BYU TV, Provo, UT | January 2015 - February 2021

- Provided a range of makeup services suitable for onscreen looks, including airbrushing, body makeup, tattoo covering, and lashes
- Collaborated with other team members to constantly improve and expand the makeup services offered
- Ensured the continuity of hair and makeup throughout Long days of shooting to teams of 20+

Makeup Artist

Utah Bride A Groom Magazine, Salt Lake City, UT | November 2009 - November 2014

- Helped models and talent maintain clean and healthy skin by introducing additional skincare products to makeup routines
- Provided makeup services to 10+ models per day
- Gained experience in bridal makeup and hair

Makeup Artist

Self Employed, Salt Lake City, UT | January 2007- November 2009

- Provided makeup services to 10+ clients per day
- Maintained at 98% customer satisfaction rate
- Used advanced preparation techniques such as exfoliation and extraction to improve makeup application